It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Shiranui Clan is about to do a full out attack on Satsumania.
지금 막 사츠마니아에 일제 공격을 하고자 하는 시라누이 일족.
Musashi tried to let Saigo know, but Hanzō caught him before he could run away.
무사시는 그걸 사이고에게 알리고자 하지만, 달아나려 하던 참에 한조에게 잡히고 만다.
Under the hypnotism of Himiko, Musashi was ordered to kill Kojirō and others.
히미코의 최면술에 걸린 무사시는 코지로 일행을 죽이라는 명령을 받고 만다.
The Last Conspiracy
시라누이 최후의
of Shiranui
음모이오
Shiro! What's wrong-gowasu?
시로! 뭔 일이오!
Kill. Kill!
죽여라. 죽여라!
Stop it, Musashi! Don't you recognize us?
관둬라, 무사시! 우리를 못 알아보겠냐!
Musashi! Stop it-gowasu!
무사시 군! 그만두시오!
If you're angry about being treated like a fool all the time, let us apologize!
아, 맨날 바보 취급했던 것에 화난 거라면 사과할게! 아니면 단고 못 먹게 한 거에 화난 거라면 그것도 사과할 테니까 용서해 줘!
It seems that Mr. Musashi is under hypnotism of some guy.
보아하니 무사시 님은 누군가의 최면술에 걸린 것 같습니다.
Then, some kind of strong shock might do.
그럼 무언가 강한 충격을 가한다면...
He will wake up by doing so.
분명 눈을 뜰 것입니다.
Come and face me, Musashi!
자, 와라, 무사시!
Ganryu! Whimsy Hit!
간류! 변덕의 히트!
Kojirō! What the heck did you just do!?
코지로! 너 뭔 짓 한 거야!
Don't worry. I used the back of my sword.
안심하세요. 칼등입니다.
You're awake-gowasu!
오, 정신이 드셨소.
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
Hey, he didn't wake up at all!
뭐야, 하나도 정신 안 차렸잖아!
I totally forgot that Musashi's nerves are insensible.
무사시의 신경이 둔한 걸 완전히 잊어먹고 있었습니다.
Kill. Kill. Kill.
죽여라. 죽여라. 죽여라.
Chest!
체스트!
Let's use this chance to make Mr. Musashi wake up.
자, 이 틈에 무사시 씨의 눈을 띄웁시다.
What is it-dasu!? Why am I in sea-dasu!?
뭣이오! 왜 내가 바다에 있소!
Huh? Are you all hiking together-dasu?
어라? 다들 모여서 하이킹 중이오?
Why are you so carefree!?
뭔 무사태평한 소리 하고 있어!
I see-dasu. I was under hypnotism-dasu...
그랬었소. 나, 최면술에 걸렸었소.
I can't forgive that Himiko as she made me try to kill everyone-dasu!
내게 모두를 죽이라게 하다니 히미코 놈 용서할 수 없소!
But, as Musashi said, if Shiranui Clan comes to attack Satsumania, it'll be a serious problem-gowasu.
그래도, 무사시 군이 말한 대로 시라누이 일족이 사츠마니아에 공격해 들어오면 큰일이오.
Mr. Musashi. Where is Shiranui Clan's base?
무사시 님. 시라누이 일족의 기지는 어디입니까?
I'll guide you-dasu!
내가 안내하오!
For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko!
히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세!
The time finally has come. It's time to build the kingdom of Shiranui in Kyushu.
드디어 때가 왔습니다. 규슈에 시라누이의 왕국을 만드는 것입니다.
Yessir! For Lord Queen Himiko!
예! 히미코 여왕님 만세!
Ms. Himiko. Everything is ready.
히미코 님. 모든 준비가 되었습니다.
Mr. Hanzō, thank you for your cooperation.
한조 님. 당신의 협력에 감사합니다.
I have a last present for you, Ms. Himiko. Please look for yourself.
히미코 님에게 최후의 선물이 있습니다. 직접 보시지요.
Mr. Hanzō, what is that?
한조 님, 저것은 무엇입니까.
That is the missile that will hit Satsumania, the central city of the kingdom of Saikai.
사이카이 왕국의 중심 도시, 사츠마니아에 향해 쏠 미사일입니다.
To Satsumania?
사츠마니아에?
Why did you make such thing?
왜 그런 것을.
To make sure the victory of our force. That one thing will make taking the whole Jipangu into our hands easier.
우리 군의 승리를 확실하게 하기 위함입니다. 이것 하나 있으면 지팡구 제국 전부를 수중에 넣기 쉬워집니다.
Using a thing like that is unforgivable.
그런 것을 쓰는 것은 용서할 수 없습니다.
Why is that, Ms. Himiko?
왜입니까, 히미코 님.
Shiranui do not wage war to kill people. Securing the land that we can live where sun shines is all we want.
시라누이는 사람을 죽이기 위해 전쟁을 하는 것이 아닙니다. 우리가 살 수 있는 태양이 닿는 장소만 확보할 수 있으면 됩니다.
For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko!
히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세!
Who's there!?
음, 누구냐!
Oh, it's you, Musashi. Did you take care of Kojirō and others?
오, 무사시구나. 코지로 일행은 잘 처리했나?
I have to report to Lord Himiko.
히미코 님에게 보고를.
Alright. You may go in.
아, 그래. 자, 들어가라.
Yes.
그렇소.
Now-dasu!
자, 지금이오!
They have so many weapons!
무기 수가 대단해!
If all of this come attack Satsumania, it'll be annihilated-gowasu.
이게 사츠마니아에 달려들면 사츠마니아는 전멸이오.
We need to move.
어떻게든 조치해야...
Leave it to me-dasu!
내게 맡기시오!
Stop it, you fool! There's no way we're going to defeat all of them by ourselves!
아, 바보야, 멈춰라! 우리가 여기서 행패부려봤자 이길 리가 없잖아!
Let's use these.
음, 이걸 씁시다.
This bomb will explode 10 minutes after setting fire.
이 폭탄을 불을 붙이고 10분 후 폭발하게 설정되어 있습니다.
If we destroy this base by installing this to various places, their scheme will come to nothing.
이걸 곳곳에 설치해 이 기지를 파괴하면 놈들의 계획도 물거품이 될 겁니다.
You're great, Mr. Jūbee! When did you get that-dasu?
역시 주베 님! 언제 그런 걸 준비했소?
My mail order has arrived yesterday.
통신 판매로 주문한 것이 어제 도착하였습니다.
Then let's divide and install.
그럼 나누어져서 설치합시다.
Who's there!?
누구냐!
Oh, it's just a rat.
뭐야, 생쥐구나.
Shiro!
시로!
Are you suggesting that this is a good place to install one-gowasu?
오, 여기에 설치하면 좋은 것인가.
Shiro is a good boy-gowasu.
역시 시로는 착한 아이이오.
(iikagen ni shiro! dajare, tūjinai de gowasu: that's enough! this word play did not work so well-gowasu)
적당히 좀 하시로! 는 말도 안 되는 말장난이오.
Something smells good-dasu.
어? 좋은 냄새가 나오.
Looks tasty-dasu!
맛있겠소!
It'll end up disappearing it explodes-dasu! I'll eat instead so that these won't be wasteful-dasu!
어차피 폭발하면 없어지오! 아까우니까 내가 먹어버리겠소!
What are you doing!? This is not a time to be snitching foods!
뭘 하고 있어! 몰래 훔쳐먹을 때가 아니잖아!?
But...
그래도...
It's all because this exists!
이런 게 있으니까 안 되는 거야!
Now, let's keep installing bombs!
자, 어서 폭탄 설치하자!
Y- yessir-dasu.
아, 알겠소.
Are you done?
거긴 어떠냐.
Good-dasu.
OK이오.
Then let's get out before it explodes-gowasu.
그럼 폭발하기 전에 빠져나가오.
The exit is on this way-dasu!
출구는 이쪽이오!
The exit is after this turn-dasu!
여기만 돌아가면 출구이오!
Huh?
어라?
Hey, you idiot! This is not an exit! This is a resting room of Shiranui!
바보야, 뭐가 출구냐! 여긴 시라누이의 휴게소잖아!
You're super ultra directionally challenged!
너 초 울트라급 길치구나?
I- I'm sorry-dasu!
미, 미안하오.
You guys dared to come into this base, but you will have no exit.
네놈들, 잘도 이 기지에 몰래 들어왔겠다. 그러나 너희에게 여기서 나갈 길은 없다.
Give up and die.
포기하고 죽어라.
Chest!
체스트!
Ms. Himiko. Please make an order for a sally.
히미코 님. 부디 출격 명령을 내려 주십시오.
No matter what you say, unless that missile is gone, I will not make such order.
에잇, 뭐라고 해도 저 미사일을 치우지 않는 한 저는 출격 명령을 내릴 수 없습니다.
But that will end up leaving big damage to our forces.
그러나 그러면 우리 군에 다수의 피해가.
To revive the Fire Country, everyone here are prepared for numerous losses.
여기 있는 모두는 불의 나라를 재건하기 위해서라면 다수의 희생은 각오하고 있습니다.
Understood. I will dispose the missile as you said, Ms. Himiko.
알겠습니다. 히미코 님이 말하는 대로 미사일은 처분하지요.
That's our Mr. Hanzō. You understand us well.
오, 그래야 한조 님. 저희을 잘 이해해 주시는군요.
Then, please make a sortie order to all forces.
그럼 전군에게 출력 명령을.
Understood.
알겠습니다.
The explosion is nearby! Wait for the stormy latter half!
폭발이 다가온다! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Shiranui Magic, Fireball Throwing Stone!
시라누이 요술, 불덩어리 돌팔매!
Chest!
체스트!
Ouchie!
아야야야야야야!
There's no end to this. Let's run!
이래선 끝이 없어. 달아나자!
Understood!
알겠습니다!
Let's run using this moment-gowasu!
이 틈에 달아나오!
I must pay back Ms. Himiko for hypnotizing me, or I can't take this-dasu!
나, 히미코 씨에게 최면술을 건 답례를 하지 않으면 못 참소!
I have something to ask-dasu.
저, 물어볼 게 있소.
Which way is Ms. Himiko's room-dasu?
히미코 씨 방 어디이오?
Oh, it's over there.
아, 그거라면 저기다.
Thank you-dasu!
땡큐이오!
Musashi!
무사시!
W- what are you doing, Hanzō!?
뭐, 뭔 짓입니까, 한조!?
If the number of soldiers decrease here,
지금 여기서 병사의 수가 적어지면 내가 지팡구국을 지배하려 할 때 부하가 적어져서 말이지.
Hanzō. Was that your true objective?
한조. 그게 당신의 목적입니까.
Himiko. I'm claiming your soldiers!
히미코. 네 병사는 내가 가져가겠다!
Hey, Himiko! How dare you hypnotize me-dasu!
야, 히미코! 잘도 내게 최면술을 걸었겠소!
That's unforgivable-dasu!
용서할 수 없소!
Huh?
어라?
What's going on-dasu?
어떻게 된 일이오?
Musashi! You were still tenaciously alive like a cockroach!
무사시! 네놈 바퀴벌레처럼 끈질기게 아직도 살아 있었냐!
Being healthy and living long are my good things-dasu!
건강하게 오래 사는 게 내 장점이오!
You're really going to the other world this time!
이번에야말로 저 세상에 보내 주겠다!
That's my line-dasu!
그건 내가 할 말이오!
Niten'ichiryū: Iron Windmill!
이천일류 철풍차!
Musashi, how dare you!
네이놈, 무사시!
Move and have your neck cut.
움직이면 목이 잘린다.
Damn! That's cowardly-dasu!
젠장! 비겁하오!
Hmph! You can list all your complaints in the other world!
흥! 불만은 저 세상에 가서 늘어놓아라!
I don't want to die yet-dasu!
으악! 나 아직 죽고 싶지 않소!
Help me, mother!
살려주시오, 엄마!
Mother!
엄마!
Farewell, Musashi!
안녕이다, 무사시!
Are you out of your mind, Himiko!?
눈이 뒤집혔나, 히미코!
Hanzō.
한조.
I- I can't let you kill Musashi.
네, 네가 무사시를 죽이도록 둘 수 없습니다.
Musashi! We'll finish this later!
무사시! 승부는 나중이다!
M- Ms. Himiko...
히, 히미코 씨...
Ms. Himiko!
히미코 씨!
Musashi. I was wrong. Hanzō was trying to use Shiranui Clan only for his own ambition.
무사시. 제가 잘못 생각하고 있었습니다. 한조는 자신의 야망만을 위해 시라누이 일족을 이용하려 하고 있었습니다.
Musashi. Will you forgive me?
무사시. 저를 용서해 주시겠습니까.
M- Musashi. Please call me mother for the last time.
무, 무사시. 마지막으로 엄마라고 불러 주세요.
Mother!
엄마!
It's a dead end-gowasu.
막장이 되어 버렸소.
Huh? Musashi's not here! I thought he was following us.
어라? 무사시가 없어. 계속 따라오고 있다고 생각했는데.
That guy has problems with following paths...
그 놈, 길치니까...
Anyway, let's get out of here. We'll end up being buried alive at this rate.
어쨌든 여기서 나갑시다. 이대로라면 생매장되어 버립니다.
You appeared again!
또 나타났구나!
You're not getting away this time!
이번에야말로 못 달아날 테다!
I'll face him for now. Please take care of Senhime.
여긴 제가 상대하겠습니다. 센히메 님을 부탁합니다.
Understood.
알겠습니다.
Kojirō, be careful!
코지로, 조심해!
I'll show you the power of Hououmaru!
봉황환의 힘을 보여주겠다!
Shiranui Magic, Fireball Throwing Stone!
시라누이 요술, 불덩어리 돌팔매!
Ganryu Tsubamegaeshi!
간류 츠바메가에시!
Who did that!?
누구냐!
It's me!
나야!
Kojirō! Now! Finish off Jinnai!
코지로! 이 틈이다! 진나이를 처치해라!
No. A martial artist cannot do a surprise attack to take down an enemy. I will have a fair and square match.
아니, 무예가라는 자가 적을 기습해서 쓰러트리는 건 할 수 없다. 정정당당히 승부한다.
That guy is too sincere. Stop, Kerokichi.
고지식한 놈. 케로키치, 스톱.
Damn!
젠장!
Now, face me!
자, 덤벼라!
Kojirō, you fool! Your sincerity will be the cause of your death! I'll make you into a fireball by my Fireball Throwing Stone!
에잇, 코지로! 네 고지식함이 네 사인이 될지어다! 불덩어리 돌팔매로 불덩어리로 만들어 주겠다!
Damn! I'm too wet to make a fireball!
아, 젠장! 물에 젖어서 불덩어리가 안 나와!
Jiraiyan, lend him your sword.
지라이얀, 네 칼을 빌려줘라.
E- excuse me...
시, 실례를...
That Kojirō guy is way too softhearted. Here you go.
코지로 놈, 어디까지 선량할 셈이냐. 자, 여기.
H- how cruel of you guys!
너, 너무한 놈들!
H- huh?
어, 어라?
J- Jiraiyan...
지, 지라이얀...
I'll have revenge for Ms. Himiko-dasu!
히미코 씨의 원수, 갚아 주겠소!
Hmph.
흥.
What the-!?
이건!
What are you trying to do-dasu!?
뭘 어쩔 생각이오!?
I'm going to take Satsumania with me.
사츠마니아를 데려갈 셈이다.
Die, Musashi!
죽어라, 무사시!
Musashi! We'll take care of this; you stop that missile!
무사시! 여긴 우리가 맡을 테니 넌 미사일을 멈춰라!
Understood-dasu!
알겠소!
I got it-dasu!
자, 잡았소!
This is strong-dasu!
힘이 세오!
Is that Musashi-gowasu?
무사시 군이오?
What are you doing over there!?
너 거기서 뭐 하고 있는 거야!?
Whatever you say, this missile won't stop-dasu!
그런 소리를 해도 미사일이 안 멈춰주오!
Mr. Musashi is trying to stop the missile, risking his life.
무사시 님은 목숨을 걸고 미사일을 멈추려고 하고 있습니다.
Musashi. You can make it.
무사시. 힘내.
What should I do-dasu? What?
어째야 좋소, 어째야...
Mommy, what's that?
엄마, 저거 뭐야?
Huh? I wonder, too!
어? 어라, 뭘까?
It will strike Satsumania directly at this rate-dasu! I must change the direction of the missile...
이대로는 사츠마니아에 명중하고 마오! 어떻게든 미사일의 방향을 바꾸기 위해선...
That's it-dasu!
그렇소!
I'm bright-dasu!
나 머리 좋소!
I did it-dasu!
해냈소!
The missile is coming back.
미사일이 돌아온다.
Musashi! Don't come to here! Go there!
무사시! 여기 오지 마! 절로 가!
-It's the missile! -Let's get out of here, Kojirō!
-미사일이다! -도망치자, 코지로!
Hanzō! We'll finish this later!
한조! 승부는 나중이다!
That's impossible!
그럴 리가!
We crushed the conspiracy of Shiranui Clan by this.
이걸로 시라누이 일족의 음모도 쳐부수었군요.
Mr. Saigo, I have a request for you-dasu.
저, 사이고 씨, 나, 사이고 씨에게 부탁이 있소만.
I already know what you want to say-gowasu.
무사시 군이 말하고 싶은 것은 알고 있소.
About the remaining Shiranui Clan...
남은 시라누이 일족 말이오.
You have nothing to worry about that-gowasu.
그거라면 걱정할 것은 없소.
They are Kyushu people. We are Kyushu people, too.
저들도 같은 규슈인. 우리도 규슈인.
They can live with us, as friends-gowasu.
지금부터는 사이좋게 같이 살아가면 되오.
Mr. Saigo, thank you-dasu!
사이고 씨, 고맙소!
Mother...
엄마...
And this is how Shiranui Clan's ambition went away.
이렇게 시라누이 일족의 야망은 사라졌다. 그렇지만 그와 함께 무사시에게 어머니의 면모를 보여 준 히미코도 떠나 버렸다.
Do not cry, Musashi. A boy grows once again when he throws away the feeling of mother.
울지 마라, 무사시. 소년은 어머니의 면모를 버릴 때부터 다시 한번 성장하는 것이다.
Get over the sadness and advance, Musashi.
슬픔을 뛰어넘어 나아가라, 무사시.
Sometimes the moon jumps over
허공의 주머니에 달이
the pocket of empty sky
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
Laugh loudly and
큰 소리로 웃으면
morning will come tomorrow
내일에는 아침이 와
Don't worry too much about losing
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Keep going! Go for it!
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
A bare hand is strong
맨손은 강해
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how life is! Look, a chance
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
follows us wagging its tail!
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
I became the number of Jipangu by taking down Kojirō!
코지로를 쓰러트리고 지팡구 제일이 된 나!
It was a long journey-dasu.
생각해보면 기나긴 여정이었소.
Kojirō is so weak-dasu!
코지로 정말 약하오!
No, no, it must be that I became strong-dasu!
아니아니, 내가 강해진 것이오, 분명!
Otsuru rushed to here with everyone in Miyamoto village, and so we're having a party-dasu!
오츠루도 급히 달려와서 미야모토 마을의 모두하고 파티이오!
By this, I can finally marry Otsuru-dasu!
이걸로 나, 드디어 오츠루하고 결혼할 수 있소!
Next story! I Defeated Kojirō!
다음 이야기! 코지로에게 이겼소!
It's stormy Otsuru-dasu!
질풍노도의 오츠루이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
I Defeated
코지로에게
Kojirō!
이겼소!
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!